朋友们 你们好
Hello, friends.
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
我叫Adrian 和我一起的是Jerry
My name is Adrian and I'm joined by Jerry.
这周我们要聊的是C418创作的 Minecraft Volume Alpha
And this week we are doing Minecraft Volume Alpha by C418.
这大概是最具标志性的配乐之一
Probably one of the most iconic soundtracks,
可以说是游戏配乐中的经典
full stop gaming soundtracks,
属于有史以来最热门的游戏之一
one of the most popular games ever.
你对《我的世界》或者它的配乐了解多少？
What do you know about Minecraft slash the soundtrack?
好吧
Okay.
嗯 《我的世界》 我算是低调的专家
Well Minecraft, I'm low-key an expert in Minecraft.
疫情期间我在线远程修了一门课
During covid I took a class in it remotely online
这样我就能让学生们创建世界 并通过它展示他们的学习成果
so that I could get my students making worlds and demonstrating their learning through it.
然后我就彻底迷上了
And I got really into it.
我们做了几个项目 后来就停了
We did a couple projects and then I just kind of stopped.
但不管怎样 回到音乐部分
But anyways, back to the music part.
所以我听过那些音乐
So I've heard the music,
其中一些 但你提到我们要做这个之前我从来没想过 我当时很困惑
some of it, but I never thought about it until you mentioned we were doing this and I was very confused.
是的 这算是个出人意料的选择 但可能会很有趣
Yeah, it's kind of a left field pick but could be fun.
我的意思是 我从小就一直在玩《我的世界》
I mean, I've been playing Minecraft since I was a kid.
我有时还会玩
Like I still play it sometimes.
我主要玩Bed Wars
I play mainly Bed Wars.
那是一个服务器上的小游戏
It's like a mini game on like a server.
总之 我很多朋友都在玩
Anyways, a lot of my friends play it.
我可能需要重新玩起来
I may need to get back into it.
Bed Wars听起来很有趣
Bed Wars sounds fun.
Bed Wars超好玩的
Bed Wars is so much fun.
有点像夺旗模式那种
It's like Capture the Flag kind of.
但是是在床上 对吧？
But in bed, right?
不 你是要保护你的床
No, you're like defending your bed.
就像你的睡觉的地方？
Like your sleeping quarters?
不……我觉得床只是一个代表生命的东西
No, it's... I think the bed is just like a placeholder for the thing that gives you life.
比如如果你失去了你的床
Like if you lose your bed,
你就不能重生了
you don't respawn.
我没有太多话要说
I don't have tons to say.
我是说 这只是一段舒缓的背景音乐
I mean, it's just a mellow soundtrack.
这对我们来说会有所不同
It's gonna be something different for us,
对于这个频道来说
for the channel.
像往常一样 完整版和其他内容都在我们的Patreon上
As always, the full version is on our Patreon along with other things.
我们先从前两首曲目开始
We'll start with the first two tracks.
所以第一首曲目是Key 第二首曲目是Door
So the first track is Key and the second track is Door.
注意到了手钟
Remind me of handbells.
是的 我的孩子们会玩它们
Yeah, my kids play them.
但就像在洞穴或什么地方
But like in like a cavern or something,
就像很远的地方
like really far away.
而且是数字的
And digital.
问题是对于很多这些歌
The problem is with a lot of these songs,
我只是想象在玩游戏
I just picture playing the game,
你知道 就像我会在做什么
you know, and like what I'd be doing.
对我来说 这感觉有点不舒服
To me, this feels uncomfortable a little bit.
那是个不错的合成器
That's a nice synth.
我有一些关于Door的问题
I have some questions about Door.
有多少乐器是真实演奏的 又有多少是通过电脑人工生成的？
How many of the instruments are actually real and how much of it is just artificially generated through computer?
人们可能会纠正我这一点
People could correct me on this,
但我很确定这完全是在电脑里完成的
but I'm pretty sure it's completely done in like a computer.
好的
Okay.
也许有些钢琴是真实的
Maybe some of the piano is real.
我不知道 但它有那种感觉
I don't know, but it has that feeling.
它确实有那种感觉
It does have that feeling.
钢琴 我在想
The piano, I was wondering,
它一开始有种日本的感觉 只是因为音符的敲击方式
it starts off it kind of Japanese feeling just because of the way the notes are struck.
我们有点知道这种情况可能会在原声带的不同部分出现
We kind of knew that this might happen at different parts in this soundtrack,
并不是说我以前没听过这个原声带
not that I've never listened to the soundtrack before,
而是我们可能不知道该说些什么
but that we might not know what the hell to say.
这可能是那种我们得在播放过程中或期间说话的事情
It might be one of those things where we have to talk through or during.
我们继续到第三首曲目
We'll move on to track three,
也就是Subwoofer Lullaby
which is Subwoofer Lullaby.
我的大脑好奇这在游戏中会如何使用
My brain wonders how this would be used in the game.
你会做什么？
What would you be doing?
你只会悲伤地看着自己造的一堵墙吗？
You'd just be sadly looking at one of the walls you created?
我觉得它就像随便什么时候播放一样
I think it just plays like whenever,
比如……
like...
你可能在挖矿 拜访村民
You could be mining, visiting villagers.
我可能是错的 但我觉得某些歌曲不是由你所做的事触发的
I could be wrong, but I don't think certain songs are triggered by what you're doing.
好吧
Okay.
非常氛围化
Very ambient.
但几乎像是一种启迪类的管风琴音乐
But almost like enlightenment kind of organ music.
我听到很多 重新听一下这个
I get a lot, just listen to this again,
比如Brian Eno 他那类氛围音乐
like Brian Eno, his like ambient stuff.
在Dora上 我听到了像是90年代的John Tesh
On Dora, I was picking up like John Tesh from the 90s,
那个弹钢琴的家伙
the piano guy.
不过我喜欢好听的钢琴
I love me a nice piano though.
它有种让人踏实的感觉 把你拉回当下
Something grounding about it brings you back.
这会是一张完美的冥想专辑
This would be a perfect meditation album.
闭上眼睛 盘腿坐下
Closed eyes, sit, crisscross applesauce,
什么都不想 冥想
think about nothing and meditate.
我觉得下次我就要用它来冥想
I think actually I'm going to use this for that next time.
实际上我在做作业或写论文的时候很喜欢用这张专辑
I actually like use this album a lot when I was like working on assignments or writing papers.
我发现它对提高效率非常有用
I find it incredible for being productive.
比如如果我在做 举个例子
Like if I'm doing, like for example,
如果我在为我们编辑缩略图
if I'm editing thumbnails for us,
我会放着氛围音乐
I'll have like ambient music on.
它让我完全沉浸其中
It just gets me locked in.
那太酷了
That's so cool.
我们这里连续来三首曲子
We'll do a three track run here.
第四首Death
We got track four, Death,
第五首Living Mice
track five, Living Mice,
还有第六首Moog City
and track six, Moog City.
那会让我暂时无法高效工作
That would make me unproductive temporarily.
你只是杀了一只鸭子什么的？
You just kill a duck or something?
我觉得是只鸡
I think a chicken.
我喜欢这段
I like this build.
关于事物也会变得平淡
Of how things go flat too.
最后一首也是
Last song too.
其实这里有很多事情在发生
There's actually a lot of stuff going on.
就像有很多小乐器进进出出
Like there's a lot of little instruments that come in and out.
我一直觉得我们得回顾一下Boards of Canada
The whole time I'm thinking we have to review Boards of Canada.
那会是个很好的选择
That would be a really good one to do.
他们属于同一类风格
They're in the same wheelhouse.
他们有相同的灵感
They have the same inspo.
不过我在想
I'm wondering though,
如果他只是在制作它
if he is just producing it,
一边演奏一边即兴 还是说他真的在写谱子
playing as he goes, or if he's actually like writing it out,
比如写总谱
like writing the score.
我想你可以两者都做
I guess you could do either,
但是有些部分实在太复杂了 就像是
but some of it's just so intricate that it's like,
他是画出来的吗？
did he draw it?
我不知道
I don't know.
大家 告诉我们吧
People, let us know.
我很好奇
I'm curious.
我完全不知道该说什么
I wouldn't know the first thing to say about that.
但这感觉像是瑞典的Hagström
But this feels Swedish Hagström.
到目前为止 这听起来真的很平静
This is a really peaceful listen so far.
是的 确实是
Yeah, it is.
是的
Yeah.
我觉得我们应该多说点什么
I feel like we should be saying more stuff about it.
我只是……
I just...
是的 很难说
Yeah, it's hard to.
确实有点难说
It is kind of hard to.
好吧 我们可以做接下来的两首
Well, we can do the next two,
第七首 Hagström
which are track 7, Hagström,
和第八首Minecraft
and track 8, Minecraft.
这是那种和你……有关的小东西之一吗？
Is this one of those little things with your...
马林巴琴？
Marimba?
不 不是马林巴琴
No, not Marimba.
是啊 我不知道
Yeah, I don't know.
我忘了那叫什么了
I forget what that's called.
会有人知道的
Someone will know.
不过话说回来 很多音符听起来像是画进去的
Then again, a lot of these notes sound like they're drawn in,
就像……不是有人在演奏 因为完全没有错误
like they're like... someone's not playing them because there's like no mistakes.
就像一切都非常
Like it's all like very,
你懂的……
you know...
数字世界
Digital world.
是啊 就像他画了进去 然后电脑在播放它们
Yeah, like he drew them in and the computer's playing them.
可能又错了
Could be wrong again,
但是……
but...
这符合你玩《我的世界》时的氛围吗？
Does this fit the vibe of you playing Minecraft?
就是说 是这个氛围吗？
Like, is this the vibe?
有点诡异和空旷
It's kind of a little bit eerie and spacey.
是的
Yeah.
我是说 我觉得确实 因为至少在原声带里 它在里面的时候不是这样的
I mean, I think it does because it's not like in at least the soundtrack when it's in there.
它并不……不会太喧宾夺主
It doesn't... it's not overpowering.
就像它更多是在背景里
Like it's more in the background.
而且显然有很多背景……或者说不算是背景
And there's obviously like tons of background... or not background.
可能又错了
Tons of sound effects of you playing the game,
比如走来走去
like walking around.
所以它就有点像叠加在那之上
So it kind of is like over top of that.
好的 所以它并不是那么突出
Okay, so this is not front and center.
这真的就是在背景里
This is like literally in the background.
是的 我是说 我觉得你可以调整它
Yeah, I mean, I think you can adjust it.
但大多数情况下
But for the most part,
我觉得游戏里其他的音效比原声带响很多
I think the other sound effects in the game are much louder than the soundtrack.
所以它更像是背景里若隐若现的那种
So it's more like subtle in the background.
有些我都不记得游戏里有
Some of them like I don't remember from the game,
不过有些确实很突出 就像那一段
which like certain ones stick out like that one.
我记得还有几个 我也不记得了
I remember a couple other ones like I didn't.
哦 我不该停掉那个的
Oh, I wasn't supposed to stop that one.
对 你确实不该
No, you weren't.
是的 那我就再开一个三曲连播
Yeah, I'll just start another three track run.
这是第八首 第九首是Oxygen 第十首是Equinox
This is track eight and then track nine is Oxygen and track ten is Equinox.
你认得这段吗？
Do you recognize this?
嗯 我觉得认得
Yeah, I think so.
已经……已经差不多
It's been... it's been almost,
嗯 五年没玩了
yeah, five years since I played.
但我觉得认得
But I think so.
这段感觉很熟悉
This feels familiar.
这不是那种典型的电子游戏配乐
It's not your typical video game soundtrack.
慢多了
Way slower.
对 更氛围感 更空旷
Yeah, much more ambient and spacious.
嗯 因为我觉得《我的世界》大多时候就是很放松
Well, because I guess a lot of Minecraft is just chill.
就像你可以随便玩玩 放空自己
Like you can just play it and be chill.
它并不是特别……
Like it's not super...
怎么说来着？
What's the, what's the term?
它是沙盒游戏
It's a sandbox game.
所以你想干嘛就干嘛
So you kind of just do whatever,
懂吧？
you know?
你看电影了吗？
Did you watch the movie?
我觉得没有
I don't think so.
可能跟我孩子看过吧
Maybe with my kids.
我不太确定
I don't know.
我看过太多儿童电影了
I've seen so many kids movies.
那也是
That's true.
我觉得我没看过
I don't think I did.
里面有蝙蝠侠吗？
Was Batman in it?
没有 那是另一部电影
No, that was something else.
那是《乐高大电影》
That's the Lego movie,
我觉得
I think.
对 就是这个
That's it.
别的积木 别的积木
Other blocks, other blocks.
一些 《我的世界》专家
Some expert in Minecraft.
我老是走神 就像在我的白日梦世界里一样
I keep getting lost, like in my daydream world.
很放松
It's very chill.
绝对是这部剧的另外一集
Definitely a different episode of the show.
是啊 挺酷的
Yeah, cool stuff.
我已经有点纠结了
I'm already struggling.
就像我脑子里在说
Like my brain's saying,
这个你给几分？
how do you rate this?
不过说真的 这绝对是我会再听的东西
But yeah, it's definitely something I'll listen to again.
我儿子睡前会听音乐
My son listens to music before bed.
我觉得我会……Alexa
I think I'll... Alexa,
播放Minecraft原声带
play Minecraft soundtrack.
它确实有点摇篮曲那种感觉
It does have like a lullaby sort of energy.
不会把我吵醒
It's not waking me up.
那是肯定的
That's for sure.
是啊
Yeah.
嗯 非常舒缓
Yeah, very low energy.
你直接让它放着就行
You could just let it play.
我不知道
I don't know.
好 那就让它放着吧
Yeah, let's just let it play.
就这样一直放着？
Just let it play throughout the whole thing?
对 我们不需要停下来讨论
Yeah, we don't need to just stop and talk about it.
哦 那又是一首我们没啥好说的歌
Oh, that was another song that we don't have much to say about,
但还挺酷的
but it was cool.
没错
That's true.
我们可以边听边聊
We can just talk throughout.
试试吧
Let's try it.
嗯 试试
Yeah, let's try it.
好
Yeah.
换点不一样的
Something different.
我们停下来的时候其实一直在重复同样的话
We're kind of saying the same thing over and over again when we stop.
至少我感觉是这样
At least I feel like I am,
但是……
but...
对
Yes.
那我们就让它一直播下去吧
So we're just gonna let it play through.
如果你想让我们停下来
And if you want us to stop,
就叫我们
just call us.
我们有热线电话
We have a hotline.
嗯哼 热线电话
Mm-hmm, hotline.
那么这是从第11首开始的
So this is track 11 onwards.
这首是 Mice On Venus
This one's Mice On Venus.
真的很喜欢我的这两首歌
I really dug both my songs.
第一首我的歌在这首我的歌里
The first my song in this my song.
这首真的很美
This one's really pretty.
不过有点苦乐参半
Kind of bittersweet, though.
有趣的小知识
Interesting factoid.
金星有失控的温室效应
Venus has a runaway greenhouse effect.
所以任何在那里的老鼠都会瞬间被烧死
So any mice on there would burn instantly.
俄罗斯人向金星发射了一个探测器 它在几秒钟内就被压缩并过热了
The Russians sent a probe to Venus and it compressed and superheated within seconds.
但它确实拍到了一些照片并传了回来
But it did get some pictures and send them back.
关于金星表面
Of the surface of Venus.
所以我们从那非常漂亮的钢琴开始 现在我们到了这里
So we start at that one really pretty piano and now we're here.
是的 我们到了
Yeah, we're here.
这是什么？
What is this?
这只是高能量的怪异
This is just high-energy weirdness.
我只是想象有人小跑着
I just picture someone trotting along.
那些弦乐
Those strings.
但高音区的那个特雷门琴
But that theremin in the top end.
有点让人不舒服
It's kind of off-putting.
我在想发生了什么
I'm wondering what's happening.
就像那个在歌曲期间一直说话的烦人的人
It's like that annoying person who keeps talking through songs.
这首叫Dry Hands
This one's called Dry Hands.
你已经猜到了吗？
Did you announce that already?
我猜是吧
I guess.
是啊 我们是不是因为必须得猜到才宣布？
Yeah, are we announcing them since we kind of have to?
我们那些悲伤的听众会想
Our sad listeners will be like,
这是什么？
what is this?
这是不是老鼠在另一个星球上？
Is this mice on another planet?
所以这首叫Dry Hands
So this one's called Dry Hands.
好的
Okay.
这是第九首
It's track 9.
10.
12.
12！
12!
时间都去哪了？
Where have the time gone?
我确实喜欢整首的钢琴音色
I do love the piano tones throughout.
是的
Yeah.
你想猜一下这首的标题吗
Did you want to announce the title of this one,
这是Wet Hands
It's Wet Hands.
聪明
Clever.
你更想要哪种？
What would you rather have?
Wet Hands还是dry hands？
Wet hands or dry hands?
dry
Dry.
但不是那种消极的干
But not like a negative dry,
比如开裂
like cracking.
只是不要湿
Just not wet.
是啊 你更想湿？
Yeah, you would prefer wet?
比起干燥裂开的手？
Over dry, cracking hands?
是的
Yes.
我开始涂保湿霜了 因为冬天太干了
I'm starting to moisturize because it's been such a dry winter.
没错
It's true.
今天有极寒警报
There's an extreme cold warning today.
是啊 我在外面待了一会儿
Yeah, I was outside for a while.
糟透了
It sucked.
幸好我手没湿
Glad I didn't have wet hands.
这首歌叫Clark
This song is called Clark.
这也是苏斯博士笔下角色的名字 他不能在天黑时出门
Which is also the name of a Dr. Seuss character who can't go out in the dark.
而且对我来说
And it was like, for me,
这是苏斯博士角色里最好玩的名字
the funnest name of a Dr. Seuss character.
Clark
Clark.
这是Clark
This is Clark.
他不能在天黑时出门
He can't go out in the dark.
很多合成器音浪
A lot of synth waves.
我觉得这是个弦乐垫
I think this is a string pad.
他们有时会用这些合成弦乐音色做背景垫
They have these pads sometimes that are like synth strings as a synth pad.
总之
Anyways.
要学的太多了
So much to learn.
这感觉像是我们第一次遇到贝斯线
This feels like the first bass line we've had.
是的
Yeah.
所以打击乐部分一直很少
So it's been very sparse on the percussion.
大概只有两首歌有某种形式的打击乐
Had like two songs with any form of that.
你把钟琴也算进打击乐吗？
Are you including bells in percussion?
我想钢琴也算吧
I guess piano also counts.
我猜是的
I guess.
对 你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
Clark是我儿子不错的睡前歌曲
Clark is a good bedtime song for my son.
这是Chris
This is Chris.
鼓刷
Brushes.
是的
Yeah.
正如我刚才所说的
Just as I was saying.
这是Thera长笛吗？
Is this the Thera Flute?
差不多吧
Something like that.
Chris真的很投入
Chris is really going for it.
Clark有点无聊
Clark was a little boring.
Chris是《我的世界》里的夜生活
Chris is nightlife in Minecraft.
这首曲目叫做13
This track is called 13.
尽管它是第16曲
Even though it's track 16.
C418真聪明
Clever C418.
聪明
Clever.
如果那是你的真名
If that is your real name.
所以 到目前为止 我觉得这很适合冥想 除了那段杀鸡的
So, so far I'm thinking this would be a great meditation thing except for that one where they kill the chicken.
死亡？
Death?
是啊 是啊
Yeah, yeah.
不过这首有点诡异
This one was eerie though.
这一首感觉……
This one felt...
没关系
That's okay.
因为不能有像“咯咯”这样的声音！
Because you can't have like a B'gok!
在中间
In the middle.
没错
True.
这首曲目叫Excuse
This track is called Excuse.
对吗？
Is that right?
还是说X-cuse？
Or is it X-cuse?
我想都有可能
I guess it could be either.
或者两者皆可
Or either.
你想说出这一首的名字吗？
Did you want to say the name of this one,
我的朋友？
my friend?
是的 这首是Sweden
Yeah, this one's Sweden.
所以我猜他一定是瑞典人
So I guess he must be Swedish.
我们有Hagstrom 也有Sweden
We had Hagstrom, we had Sweden.
我们有Chris
We had Chris.
这是瑞典名字 对吧？
It's a Swedish name, isn't it?
Chris！
Chris!
是的 这首也相当经典
Yeah, this one's a pretty iconic one too.
天哪
Man.
一些音效
Some hits.
钢琴音效
Piano hits.
是的 这不是排行榜上的
Yeah, this is not charting.
我想知道这首是否曾经上过榜单
I wonder if this hit the charts at one point.
也许吧
Maybe.
这张专辑肯定有混音版
There's got to be like a remix of this album.
你知道 可能有个house混音或者什么的
You know, there's probably like a house remix or something.
是的 有几次我都想在里面加些东西
Yeah, there's a couple of times where I wanted to drop some stuff in there.
这与我们通常做的音乐太不一样了
It's such a departure from the music we normally do.
我知道 这非常不同
I know, this is very different.
非常不同
Very different.
可能这是我们迄今为止最放松的一集
Probably our most relaxed episode yet.
这首歌完全给人一种猫的感觉
This song is totally giving cat vibes.
总是忙着蹦来蹦去
Always busy bouncing around.
是的 这可以在猫的头上播放
Yeah, this could be playing on a cat's head.
是的
Yeah.
我觉得这是猫核
I feel like this is catcore.
这很有电子游戏的感觉
This is very video game-y.
这些音符几乎就像...
The notes are almost like...
比特
bits.
是的 像8-bit
Yeah, like 8-bit.
非常嗡嗡作响 那种街机风格
Very buzzy and that sort of arcade-y thing.
是的
Yeah.
我也记得 比如
I remember too, like,
玩最初的电子游戏时 完全沉浸其中
playing the first video games and being so locked into the game.
就像真的一样
It was like real.
然后当你环顾四周时
And then when you looked around,
你就会想 哦对
you're like, oh yeah,
对
right.
好吧
All right.
不过我确实很喜欢这些合成器
I do love these synths though.
我刚想说 我和女朋友最喜欢的消遣之一就是玩……
I was going to say, one of my girlfriend and I's favorite pastime is playing...
使命召唤：僵尸
Call of Duty Zombies.
我们经常玩那个
We do that a lot.
什么？
What?
在Xbox上？
On Xbox?
对
Yeah.
我和我儿子玩《老虎伍兹高尔夫》
I do Tiger Woods Golf with my son.
PS1赛车
PS1 Racing.
这首歌叫Dog 是第18首曲目
This song's called Dog and it's track number 18,
大概吧
I guess?
19.
不 是20
No, 20.
20？！
20?!
是的 我们快结束了
Yeah, we're nearing the end.
这根本不像Dog
This is so not Dog.
我的狗就像……
My dogs are like...
我的狗不是那种沉稳的
My dogs are not composed.
疯狂的小毛球 充满愤怒
Crazy little fluff balls of fury.
我相当肯定在游戏早期版本里
I'm pretty sure in the early versions of the game,
你能拥有的宠物只有猫和狗
the only two pets you could have are cat and dog.
所以这可能是它们的音乐
So maybe this is cued by them.
我不知道
I don't know.
你驯服……
You tame...
但当你杀死游戏里的骷髅时
But when you kill a skeleton in the game,
当它们是夜间生物之一时
when it's one of the mobs at night,
你会得到骨头
you get bones.
所以你就是那样把狼驯养成宠物的
So that's how you tame the wolves into being your pet.
然后对于猫 我觉得你得抓鱼
And then for cats, I think you have to get fish.
人类就是这样让最早的狼变成狗的
That's how humans got the first wolves to be dogs.
他们会有那些垃圾堆 人类把废弃物倒在那里 然后狼就待在那里
They'd have these trash piles where humans would dump the refuse and then the wolves would hang out there.
然后你们越来越接近彼此 互相习惯 最终它们开始成为宠物
Then you'd get closer and closer to each other and get used to each other and eventually they started being pets.
真疯狂
That's crazy.
当其他动物来的时候
When other animals would come,
狼会叫 所以人类看到了拥有的价值……
the wolves would bark so the humans saw value in having...
像是警报
Like an alert.
是啊
Yeah.
但它们也帮助打猎
But they help with the hunt.
摸它们很好玩
They're fun to pet.
你不觉得这抓住了狗的顽皮天性吗？
Do you not think this captures the playful nature of a dog though?
是的
Yeah.
我真的很喜欢……不过我喜欢这两个
I really like... I like these two though.
我喜欢猫和狗
I like cat and dog.
它们很有趣
They're fun.
这些曲子很好听
They're fun tunes.
哦 是啊 我同意
Oh, yeah, I agree.
这个……不过我不知道它适不适合冥想
This... I don't know if it would work for meditation though.
是的 适合
Yep, it would.
我确实喜欢它的一点是整首曲子都很有旋律感
What I do like about it throughout the whole thing is that it's like melodic.
就像总是有一条旋律可以跟着
Like there's like always like a melody to follow.
而且他常常在整首曲子中重复这个旋律
And one that he'll often repeat throughout the tune,
这很好
which is nice.
所以它不只是……只是和弦
So it's not just like... just like chords.
它就像 你知道的
It's just like, you know,
有个东西可以抓一抓
there's something to grab onto a little bit.
同意
Agreed.
然后你会在旋律上下听到这些美妙的加花 令人兴奋
And then you get these nice fills above and below the melody that are exciting.
这首叫Danny
This one's called Danny.
很多名字
A lot of names.
是的 这些歌让我回到了从前
Yeah, these songs take me back.
我小的时候 我父母在家里的电脑上设置了家长控制
When I was younger, my parents had parental controls on the family computer.
哦 太好了
Oh, good.
是啊
Yeah.
所以我们每天只允许大概30分钟
So we only allowed like 30 minutes per day.
而且我经常和朋友打电话玩《我的世界》
And I would play Minecraft with my friends over the phone all the time.
比如在Mineplex上玩《饥饿游戏》
Like playing Hunger Games on Mineplex.
那是一个服务器 你只要……就像《饥饿游戏》
It's like a server where you just... it's like Hunger Games,
但是在《我的世界》里
but in Minecraft.
哦 酷
Oh, cool.
太好玩了
It's so fun.
这就是我喜欢《我的世界》的地方
That's what I like about Minecraft.
你总能和别人一起玩
You can always play with people.
这是第23首？
This is track 23?
第22首
22.
我永远都猜不对
I'm never gonna guess right.
第22首Beginning
Track 22, Beginning.
我觉得《我的世界》
I think also Minecraft,
在新冠疫情期间 他们联系教育工作者 让我们在课堂上使用《我的世界》
they tapped educators at this time during COVID to get us to use Minecraft in classes
因为孩子们反正都在家对着电脑
because kids were at home on theircomputers anyway.
他们想推广它
They were trying to grow it.
所以后来我确实给想做的孩子们布置了《我的世界》作业
So then I did assign Minecraft assignments to kids who wanted them.
而且我得到了一些很棒的作品
And I got some really good stuff.
他们建造了世界
They built worlds.
是的
Yeah.
然后发给我 再一起讨论
Then sent them to me and then talked about them.
那很酷
That's cool.
这首叫Droopy Likes Ricochet
This one's Droopy Likes Ricochet.
谁不喜欢好的弹跳声呢？
Who doesn't like a good ricochet?
对吧？
Right?
打击乐
Percussion.
是的 我记得我一直很喜欢最后两首
Yeah, I always remember liking the last two a lot.
打击乐是核心
Percussion is the forefront.
这让我想起治疗乐队的Pictures of You
This reminds me of the Cure Pictures of You,
这也提醒我我们还没做过治疗乐队的专辑
which also reminds me we haven't done a Cure album yet either.
我知道
I know.
我知道有……确实是这样
I know there's... it's true.
我们还需要做太多专辑了
So many albums we need to do.
Droopy Likes Your Face
Droopy Likes Your Face.
第24首
Track 24.
总算说对了一次
Got it right for once.
所以在Ricochet之后是Droopy Likes Your Face
So post-Ricochet, Droopy Likes Your Face.
这是第一次出现人声吗？
Is this the first voice?
是的 如果不算那只鸡的话
Yeah, if you don't include the chicken.
我觉得也可以算
I guess you could.
只认为人声才算声音 这很人类中心主义
Very anthro-centric to think only human voices.
算上吧
Count.
这可以说是有点吓人
This could be considered terrifying.
就像某种恶魔般的低语
It's like some like demonic whispers.
是的
Yeah.
不过配上很悦耳的器乐
Over really pleasant instrumental though.
恶魔版的史蒂芬·霍金
Demonic Stephen Hawking.
有点史蒂芬·霍金内核的感觉
It's kind of Stephen Hawking core.
所以这就是我们Minecraft volume alpha体验
So that's our Minecraft volume alpha experience.
真是一段难忘的体验
What an experience it was.
我很抱歉自己说了太多话
I feel bad about how much I talked through it,
但还是很棒的
but it was good though.
我喜欢
I liked it.
我会再听一遍 当作冥想
Like I'm gonna listen to this again as meditation.
这是很适合播放的好音乐
It's good music to have on.
我坚持这个看法
Like I stand by it.
如果你在做事的时候放这个很不错
It's like nice to put on if you're doing something.
显然 我从游戏里就熟悉它了
Obviously, I'm familiar with it from the game,
但是作为背景音乐 这真的是非常可爱的氛围音乐
but it's just really lovely ambient music to have on.
确实是可爱的氛围音乐
It is lovely ambient music to have on.
我们来打个分吧
Let's get to rating here.
比如说 和我们听过的其他东西相比 你会怎么评价这个？
Like, how do you rate something like this vis-a-vis everything else we've listened to?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不知道该怎么评价这个
I don't know how to rate this.
对我们节目来说 这完全是另一个领域
It's a different field completely for our show.
所以怎么说？
So like what?
我给B？
Do I say B?
我给A？
Do I say A?
我给……
Do I say...
它不是S级 但对某些人来说可能是S级
It's not S, but it could be S to someone.
John Tesh大概会很喜欢
John Tesh would probably really like it.
我不知道 兄弟
I don't know, dude.
你心里怎么想就怎么来
Do whatever your heart is feeling.
我心里什么感觉都没有
My heart doesn't feel anything.
你会打多少分？
What would you rate it?
我跟你一样
I'll copy you.
你要抄我的？
You're gonna copy me?
不
No.
好吧 行
Okay, fine.
我的意思是……
I mean...
我不知道
I don't know.
B？
B?
那不就得了
There you go.
我想我要给S+
I think I'm gonna go S+.
很难打分 但是呢
It's hard to rate, but like,
我真的说不出任何负面评价
there's nothing negative I could say about it,
真的 因为这是原声带
really, because it's a soundtrack.
嗯 我确实 我爱它
Like, and I do, I love it.
嗯 它真的 就像
Like, it's really, like,
这是我在工作时经常听的东西之一
it's one of my things that I listen to a lot when I'm doing work.
但它不需要专心听
But it requires no audio.
放在背景里很不错
It's nice to have in the background.
音效设计很棒
The sound design is awesome.
非常精妙
It's very intricate.
我喜欢它自始至终对旋律的专注
I love the focus on melody throughout.
就是他带进带出的那些非常优美的旋律线
Just very pretty little lines that he brings in and out.
无可挑剔
No complaints.
这很难评论
It's hard to comment on,
比如 当有氛围音乐时
like, ambient music when there's,
你知道 更关注的是氛围和
you know, the more focus is the atmosphere and,
就像 那种感觉
like, the feeling.
而且我觉得它让人安心 只是因为
And I find it comforting just because,
我想 我是玩着这款游戏长大的
I guess, I grew up playing the game.
所以 这就是我对它的看法
So that's, like, my approach to it.
但我确实认为它很适合那种
But I do think it lends itself to that kind of,
我不想说怀旧
I don't want to say nostalgia,
因为对我来说 那就是怀旧
because it's nostalgia for me,
但这就有点像 苦乐参半
but it's, like, kind of bittersweet,
略带忧郁的声音
slightly melancholic sound.
我确实很喜欢所有的钢琴部分
I do love all the piano parts,
但我喜欢它 因为我也喜欢做氛围音乐
but I love it because I like making ambient music too.
所以我想这一首也是
So I guess this one also,
比如 有很多可以从中学习的东西
like, lots to be learned from it.
好的 对我来说就是这样
Okay, for me in that way.
这是不同的东西
It's something different.
我们在尝试一些不同的东西
We were trying something different.
那是不同的一集
It was a different episode,
但是非常感谢你加入我们的Minecraft
but thank you so much for joining us on Minecraft.
一如既往 我是说 完整版在我们的Patreon上
As always, I mean, the full versions on our Patreon.
我是说 谢谢你的加入
I mean, thanks for joining us.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
下次见
Until next time.
再见
Bye bye.
回头见
See ya.
原标题：High School Teacher vs C418 - 'Minecraft - Volume Alpha' 原作者：Ear Candy
原视频上传日期：2026年2月21日
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
有能力的请到Youtube上支持原作者
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！(*ﾟ∀ﾟ*)